=Within The Grip=
=داخل القبضة=
=Episode 23=
=الحلقة 23=
(Play the Long Game)
(العب لعبة طويلة الأمد)
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will)
(عقل واسع، إرادة أبدية)
♪Stroke by stroke, bit by bit♪
♪ ضربة تلو الأخرى، شيئًا فشيئًا ♪
(Don't be afraid. I'll bring you home.)
(لا تخف. سأعيدك إلى المنزل.)
(If you have nowhere to go, why not return with me and secure employment?)
(إذا لم يكن لديك مكان تذهب إليه، فلماذا لا تعود معي وتحصل على وظيفة؟)
What task?
ما هي المهمة؟
Be my husband.
كن زوجي.
(Since you already mirror him closely,)
(بما أنك بالفعل تشبهه إلى حد كبير،)
I'll perfect your resemblance.
سأتقن الشبه بينكما.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
It's chilly at night, so I brought you a cloak.
الجو بارد في الليل، لذلك أحضرت لك عباءة.
♪Writing our unfinished story♪
♪نكتب قصتنا غير المكتملة♪
(It occurs to me that you're much more likable)
(يخطر ببالي أنك أكثر جاذبية بكثير)
(when you're quiet.)
(عندما تكون هادئاً.)
(Start by calling me "dear"?)
(هل تبدأ بمناداتي بـ "عزيزي"؟)
♪This moment weaves eternity♪
♪هذه اللحظة تنسج الأبدية♪
Dear.
عزيزي.
(A man, no matter how gentle his nature,)
(الرجل، مهما كانت طبيعته لطيفة،)
should protect his own wife.
عليه أن يحمي زوجته.
♪Like rain seeping into the earth♪
♪كالمطر الذي يتسرب إلى الأرض♪
(Are you just using me)
(هل تستغلني فقط؟)
and then throwing me away?
ثم يرمونني بعيداً؟
(Honey, what more do you want?)
(عزيزتي، ماذا تريدين أكثر من ذلك؟)
(Is this enough?)
(هل هذا كافٍ؟)
♪Helplessly falling for you♪
♪أقع في حبك بلا حول ولا قوة♪
(Everyone has secrets.)
(لكل شخص أسراره.)
(Regardless of our goals,)
(بغض النظر عن أهدافنا،)
we're allies for now.
نحن حلفاء في الوقت الحالي.
(Best not to pry too deeply.)
(من الأفضل عدم الخوض في التفاصيل بعمق شديد.)
Just go. Don't worry about me.
اذهب فحسب. لا تقلق عليّ.
♪Let time rush by♪
دع الوقت يمر سريعاً
How could I leave you behind?
كيف لي أن أتركك خلفي؟
(Don't worry. I'll be right back.)
(لا تقلق. سأعود حالاً.)
Dear.
عزيزي.
♪A love poem awaits our rediscovery♪
♪قصيدة حب تنتظر إعادة اكتشافنا♪
Was I too heavy-handed?
هل كنتُ قاسياً جداً؟
No, something just got in my eye.
لا، لقد دخل شيء ما في عيني.
(Let me blow it out.)
(دعني أنفخها.)
♪Carving a monument of longing♪
♪نحت نصب تذكاري للشوق♪
Spring Fever is the strongest love drug at Zuixian Building.
حمى الربيع هي أقوى مخدر للحب في مبنى زويشيان.
Specifically used to tame resistant men.
يستخدم خصيصاً لترويض الرجال العنيدين.
What should be done then?
ماذا ينبغي فعله إذن؟
Beg me.
توسل إليّ.
♪I've failed you♪
لقد خذلتك
♪Pour this worldly brew♪
♪اسكب هذا المشروب العالمي♪
♪I raise my cup♪
أرفع كأسي
♪Accompany you through ups and downs♪
♪نرافقك في السراء والضراء♪
♪Tears of romance♪
دموع الحب
♪You smile so sadly♪
♪تبتسمين بحزن شديد♪
(You should know this isn't compassion.)
(يجب أن تعلم أن هذا ليس تعاطفاً.)
(In this world of power,)
(في عالم السلطة هذا،)
(instead of killing someone,)
(بدلاً من قتل شخص ما،)
(why not turn them into a blade in your hands?)
(لماذا لا تحولها إلى نصل في يديك؟)
(It's clear the latter benefits more.)
(من الواضح أن الخيار الأخير يحقق فوائد أكثر.)
(But...)
(لكن...)
(I'm nothing but a blade in someone else's hands.)
(أنا لست سوى سيف في يد شخص آخر.)
♪Drunk for you♪
♪سكران لأجلك♪
And you?
وأنت؟
Have you ever truly cared for me?
هل اهتممت بي حقاً يوماً ما؟
♪Our deep affection is an endless ode♪
♪محبتنا العميقة هي قصيدة لا تنتهي♪
♪Can't escape parting in this lifetime♪
لا مفر من الفراق في هذه الحياة
♪Meet again in the next life♪
♪نلتقي مجدداً في الحياة الأخرى♪
Don't leave.
لا تغادر.
I won't leave.
لن أغادر.
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will) (You don't ask where I'm going?)
(عقل واسع، إرادة أبدية) (ألا تسأل إلى أين أنا ذاهب؟)
No matter where you go, I will wait here for your return.
أينما ذهبت، سأنتظرك هنا حتى عودتك.
♪Tears of romance♪
دموع الحب
(Who would've thought my frail husband)
(من كان ليظن أن زوجي الضعيف سيفعل ذلك؟)
(possesses such skills?)
(هل يمتلك مثل هذه المهارات؟)
(Shouldn't you be resting?)
(ألا ينبغي عليك أن تستريح؟)
Why the night stroll in black clothes?
لماذا التجول ليلاً بالملابس السوداء؟
Likewise.
على نفس المنوال.
Since you already know,
بما أنك تعلم بالفعل،
shall we work together from now on?
هل نتعاون معاً من الآن فصاعداً؟
♪This sorrow♪
♪هذا الحزن♪
Go...
يذهب...
♪Drunk for you♪
♪سكران لأجلك♪
And hurry back.
وأسرع بالعودة.
May I kiss you?
هل لي أن أقبلك؟
Dear.
عزيزي.
♪Our deep affection is an endless ode♪
♪محبتنا العميقة هي قصيدة لا تنتهي♪
♪Can't escape parting in this lifetime♪
لا مفر من الفراق في هذه الحياة
♪Meet again in the next life♪
♪نلتقي مجدداً في الحياة الأخرى♪
♪Do you know my feelings♪
♪هل تعرف مشاعري♪
Qi and that Mr. Gu
تشي والسيد غو
have been settled as you instructed.
تم تسويتها كما طلبت.
Understood.
مفهوم.
Do you have any other instructions?
هل لديك أي تعليمات أخرى؟
You may leave.
يمكنك المغادرة.
Should we clean up the wedding items in the Fufeng Pavilion?
هل يجب علينا تنظيف أغراض الزفاف في جناح فوفينغ؟
No.
لا.
Check when the next auspicious date is.
تحقق من موعد التاريخ الميمون التالي.
Yes.
نعم.
Dear.
عزيزي.
Do you truly refuse to believe me?
هل ترفض حقاً تصديقي؟
Very well.
جيد جدا.
Xuan Qing.
شوان تشينغ.
Dear.
عزيزي.
Is the bracelet I once meant to give you still there?
هل ما زال السوار الذي كنت أنوي أن أهديه لك موجوداً؟
What are your orders, Master Zhaoxi?
ما هي أوامرك يا سيد تشاوكسي؟
I never imagined that after our brief separation,
لم أتخيل أبداً أنه بعد انفصالنا القصير،
I'd return to find everything so changed.
سأعود لأجد كل شيء قد تغير.
Master Zhaoxi, don't overthink it.
يا سيد تشاوكسي، لا تُبالغ في التفكير.
I've arranged for a new auspicious date to complete our wedding ceremony.
لقد رتبت موعداً جديداً وميموناً لإتمام مراسم زفافنا.
Now, I've become like this.
لقد أصبحتُ الآن على هذا النحو.
Are you still willing to marry me?
هل ما زلتِ ترغبين بالزواج مني؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Don't you want to marry me?
ألا تريدين الزواج بي؟
Yes.
نعم.
I just...
أنا فقط...
Master Zhaoxi, don't worry. Return and focus on recovering.
لا تقلق يا سيد تشاوكسي. عد وركز على التعافي.
When we reset the auspicious date, it will be time for our wedding.
عندما نعيد تحديد التاريخ الميمون، سيحين موعد زفافنا.
Acting Master.
أستاذ بالنيابة.
Did you see Mr. Gu Xuanwu?
هل رأيت السيد قو شوانوو؟
No.
لا.
Truly? Or do you refuse to mention him?
حقاً؟ أم أنك ترفض ذكره؟
For the Pavilion Master position,
بالنسبة لمنصب مدير الجناح،
you challenged above your rank
لقد تحديت ما هو أعلى من رتبتك
and even killed your newlywed husband.
بل وقتلت زوجك حديث الزواج.
Would you spare Mr. Gu Xuanwu, your rival?
هل ستعفو عن السيد غو شوانوو، خصمك؟
You truly stop at nothing.
أنت حقاً لا تتوقف عند أي شيء.
You'd sacrifice your own comrades to achieve your goals.
ستضحي برفاقك لتحقيق أهدافك.
Stopping at nothing to achieve one's aims.
عدم التوقف عند أي شيء لتحقيق الأهداف.
Isn't that what the Pavilion taught us?
أليس هذا ما علمنا إياه الجناح؟
You call me Acting Master.
أنت تناديني بالسيد بالنيابة.
Now, questioning me means questioning the Pavilion itself.
الآن، إن استجوابي يعني استجواب الجناح نفسه.
My rise, my marriage. They are my choices.
صعودي، زواجي. هما خياري.
But have you ever chosen anything for yourselves?
لكن هل سبق لكم أن اخترتم شيئاً لأنفسكم؟
Have you heard? The Young Madam is marrying again.
هل سمعتم؟ السيدة الشابة ستتزوج مرة أخرى.
Because the family head promised
لأن رب الأسرة وعد
to hand over the Xuanji Pavilion to her only after the wedding.
أن يتم تسليم جناح شوانجي لها فقط بعد الزفاف.
Does she desire the position that desperately?
هل ترغب في هذا المنصب بشدة؟
Just days ago, I saw her deeply affectionate with that man.
قبل أيام قليلة فقط، رأيتها وهي تُظهر عاطفة عميقة تجاه ذلك الرجل.
Who could've imagined she'd...?
من كان ليتخيل أنها ستفعل ذلك؟
She's doing this
إنها تفعل هذا
just for the Pavilion and the Gu family, isn't she?
أليست تفعل ذلك فقط من أجل الجناح وعائلة غو؟
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
Twenty strokes for both and then kick them out.
عشرون ضربة لكليهما ثم طردهما.
We don't need backbiting servants.
لسنا بحاجة إلى خدم ينمّون على الآخرين.
- Spare us!
ارحمنا!
Master.
يتقن.
I hear you're picking a wedding date.
سمعت أنكِ بصدد اختيار موعد الزفاف.
Are you really going to...?
هل ستفعل ذلك حقاً؟
I was originally assigned to Master Zhaoxi by the family head.
تم تعييني في الأصل للسيد تشاوكسي من قبل رئيس العائلة.
Now that he's returned, the wedding must proceed.
والآن بعد عودته، يجب أن يتم الزفاف.
But the next auspicious date is half a month away.
لكن الموعد الميمون التالي بعد نصف شهر.
You could...
يمكنك...
Three days have already passed. I can't wait that long.
لقد مرّت ثلاثة أيام بالفعل. لا أستطيع الانتظار كل هذا الوقت.
Set it for three days from now.
اضبطه على ثلاثة أيام من الآن.
Why such urgency?
لماذا هذه الاستعجال؟
(When will the frost and snow return?)
(متى سيعود الصقيع والثلج؟)
(May we meet again)
(عسى أن نلتقي مجدداً)
(when spirits return.)
(عندما تعود الأرواح.)
Three days isn't enough to remake a wedding gown.
ثلاثة أيام لا تكفي لإعادة تصميم فستان زفاف.
No need to remake it.
لا حاجة لإعادة صنعه.
But your wedding gown is stained with blood.
لكن فستان زفافك ملطخ بالدماء.
Just purchase any suitable set.
ما عليك سوى شراء أي مجموعة مناسبة.
Are you absolutely certain?
هل أنت متأكد تماماً؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Zhaoxi...
تشاوكسي...
I meant the groom you bowed with.
كنت أقصد العريس الذي انحنيت معه.
He...
هو...
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
(Some words, some things,)
(بعض الكلمات، بعض الأشياء،)
(once missed, bring endless regret.)
(إذا فاتتك الفرصة، ستجلب ندمًا لا ينتهي.)
(Xuanji Pavilion)
(جناح شوانجي)
Have you truly
هل أنت حقاً
made up your mind?
هل حسمت أمرك؟
Yes.
نعم.
(Pavilion Master's Token)
(رمز سيد الجناح)
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will)
(عقل واسع، إرادة أبدية)
Master Zhaoxi.
سيد تشاو شي.
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Master, Madam,
سيدي، سيدتي،
why did you both go out?
لماذا خرجتما معاً؟
On this joyous day, don't miss the auspicious hour.
في هذا اليوم السعيد، لا تفوت الساعة الميمونة.
I left the hairpin Xuanji gave me in the room.
تركت دبوس الشعر الذي أعطاني إياه شوانجي في الغرفة.
It's merely a hairpin. Don't delay the moment.
إنها مجرد دبوس شعر. لا تضيع الفرصة.
I noticed you'd forgotten the hairpin.
لاحظت أنك نسيت دبوس الشعر.
You go ahead. I'll get it now.
تفضل أنت. سأحضره الآن.
Thank you, Master Zhaoxi.
شكرا لك، سيد تشاوشي.
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will)
(عقل واسع، إرادة أبدية)
(Combination lock)
(قفل برقم سري)
(Pavilion Master's Token)
(رمز سيد الجناح)
Master Zhaoxi, the time has arrived.
يا سيد تشاوكسي، لقد حان الوقت.
This...
هذا...
Master, I've succeeded and brought back
سيدي، لقد نجحت وأعدت
the Xuanji Pavilion Master's Token as ordered.
رمز سيد جناح شوانجي كما هو مطلوب.
Present it.
قدمها.
Yes.
نعم.
(Pavilion Master's Token)
(رمز سيد الجناح)
Where is he?
أين هو؟
I'll go check immediately.
سأذهب لأتحقق من الأمر فوراً.
Master!
يتقن!
Master Zhaoxi has disappeared.
اختفى المعلم تشاوكسي.
The room is a mess. The secret compartment was opened.
الغرفة في حالة فوضى. تم فتح الخزانة السرية.
The thing inside is gone.
الشيء الموجود بالداخل قد اختفى.
You may leave.
يمكنك المغادرة.
Yes.
نعم.
What was in the secret compartment?
ماذا كان موجوداً في الحجرة السرية؟
The token.
الرمز المميز.
The Xuanji Pavilion follows the Master's Token, not the person.
يتبع جناح شوانجي رمز السيد، وليس الشخص.
Think carefully about where the token is now.
فكّر جيداً في مكان وجود الرمز الآن.
No one blocks me today!
لا أحد يحجبني اليوم!
When my master returns, you will die.
عندما يعود سيدي، ستموت.
I withheld this earlier to avoid disrupting everyone's plans.
لقد أخفيت هذا الأمر سابقاً لتجنب تعطيل خطط الجميع.
I'm uncertain if the one who returned is Zhaoxi.
لست متأكدًا مما إذا كان الشخص الذي عاد هو تشاوكسي.
But you are absolutely not Qi.
لكنك لستَ تشي على الإطلاق.
Qi once confronted me over his pay.
واجهني تشي ذات مرة بشأن راتبه.
I wanted to whip him,
أردت أن أجلده،
but I accidentally left a scar behind his ear.
لكنني تركت ندبة خلف أذنه عن طريق الخطأ.
The other day, I happened to notice
في أحد الأيام، لاحظت بالصدفة
there was nothing behind your ear.
لم يكن هناك شيء خلف أذنك.
Allowing thieves to escape
السماح للصوص بالفرار
and bowing to whoever holds the token?
والانحناء لمن يحمل الرمز؟
Wouldn't that make the Xuanji Pavilion a laughingstock?
ألن يجعل ذلك جناح شوانجي مثار سخرية؟
The winner takes all.
الفائز يحصل على كل شيء.
Since the token has changed hands,
بما أن الرمز قد تم تداوله بين أيدٍ مختلفة،
whoever possesses it commands the Pavilion.
من يمتلكها يسيطر على الجناح.
Now, the token is in my master's hands.
الآن، الرمز في يد سيدي.
Wise ones will step aside now!
سيتنحى الحكماء جانباً الآن!
After Chief He's death, I was rendered powerless.
بعد وفاة الزعيم هي، أصبحت عاجزاً تماماً.
You did very well.
أحسنت صنعا.
After taking the Xuanji Pavilion and the Gu family, I need a manager.
بعد الاستيلاء على جناح شوانجي وعائلة غو، أحتاج إلى مدير.
You will be...
ستكون...
No.
لا.
Then what is this?
إذن ما هذا؟
(Pavilion Master's Token)
(رمز سيد الجناح)
What? Impossible!
ماذا؟ مستحيل!
The token is forged from iron. How could it be this light?
صُنعت هذه القطعة من الحديد. كيف يمكن أن تكون بهذا الخفة؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
You fool!
يا أحمق!
Huan, I trust you've been well?
هوان، أثق أنك بخير؟
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪تتمايل أغصان الصفصاف في نسيم الغسق♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪الأزقة القديمة تحرس أسرار الزمن♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪الأحجار الزرقاء تحمل بصمات الحياة♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪بتلات متساقطة، شوق لا ينتهي♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪الشوق يتردد في قلبي♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪تتنهد أوتار القيثارة على فراق الحزن♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪حكايات الماضي تسكن روحي♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪تبقى المودة خالدة، لا تُنسى♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪مخطوطات ملطخة بالحبر تستحضر الماضي♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪كل ضربة تحمل فكرة♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪الرخاء يتلاشى كالأحلام♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪حكايات الماضي تسكن روحي♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪تبقى المودة خالدة، لا تُنسى♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪مخطوطات ملطخة بالحبر تستحضر الماضي♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪كل ضربة تحمل فكرة♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪الرخاء يتلاشى كالأحلام♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪حكايات الماضي تسكن روحي♪